<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">PMDM_Tarea2</string>
    <string name="WelcomeToast">Welcome to Mario World</string>
    <string name="CharacterSelected">Selected character</string>
    <string name="Close">Close</string>
    <string name="open_drawer">Open menu</string>
    <string name="close_drawer">Close menú</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="about">About app</string>
    <string name="changeLang">Español</string>
    <string name="DialogText">App developer\nJuan Pedro Ruiz Rabadán\n\n1.0 version</string>
    <string name="Name">Name</string>
    <string name="CharacterList">Characters</string>
    <string name="Role">Role</string>
    <string name="Ally">Ally</string>
    <string name="Enemy">Enemy</string>
    <string name="Skill">Skill</string>
    <string name="Description">Description</string>
    <string name="MarioName">Mario</string>
    <string name="MarioSkill">Plumber</string>
    <string name="LuigiName">Luigi</string>
    <string name="LuigiSkill">Plumber</string>
    <string name="PeachName">Peach</string>
    <string name="PeachSkill">Mushroom Kingdom Princess</string>
    <string name="YoshiName">Yoshi</string>
    <string name="YoshiSkill">Transportation dinosaur</string>
    <string name="ToadName">Toad</string>
    <string name="ToadSkill">Mushroom Kingdom people</string>
    <string name="BowserName">Bowser</string>
    <string name="BowserSkill">Archenemy of Mario</string>
    <string name="MarioDescription"><![CDATA[<b>Mario</b> is the protagonist of the Mario video game series and Nintendo\'s mascot. He was created by <b>Shigeru Miyamoto</b> in 1981 and made his first appearance in the arcade game <b>Donkey Kong</b>. He is an Italian-American plumber who currently lives in the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b>. As a hero, he is responsible for saving people, especially <b>Princess Peach</b>, whom he has saved many times from the clutches of the fearsome <b>Bowser</b>, who is his arch-enemy. <br/><br/>He is a humble and good-hearted person, who doesn\'t mind how far he has to go to save people who need his help. <br/><br/>He has gained a lot of acceptance and appreciation since his beginnings, and is even considered the most famous video game character. <br/><br/><b>Mario</b> is a kind, brave, patient, and loyal hero with a strong sense of justice, morality, and goodness, and a great character. He always puts the needs and problems of others before his own. He is willing to risk his life to save millions from the forces of evil. Being heroic, he is dedicated to rescuing <b>Princess Peach</b> from the clutches of <b>Bowser</b> or other villains. <br/><br/>If there\'s something <b>Mario</b> likes more than defeating <b>Bowser</b>, it\'s going on vacation. <b>Mario</b> always brings joy wherever he goes and always has good intentions. <br/><br/>He is compassionate towards others, and has good camaraderie with his brother <b>Luigi</b>, whom he greatly appreciates. Being the older brother and a proclaimed hero, he often shows good leadership qualities. Despite being widely proclaimed, <b>Mario</b> is humble with his achievements and enjoys a quiet life with his friends.]]></string>
    <string name="LuigiDescription"><![CDATA[<b>Luigi</b> is Mario\'s younger brother in Nintendo\'s video games. He first appeared in the 1983 arcade game, Mario Bros, then in Super Mario Bros. As the second player, a role he continued to play in Super Mario Bros 3 and Super Mario World. The name <b>Luigi</b> was inspired by a pizza restaurant near the headquarters of Nintendo of America in Redmond, Washington, called <b>&quot;Mario &amp; Luigi\'s&quot;</b>.<br/><br/> <b>Luigi</b> is a video game character created by <b>Shigeru Miyamoto</b>. He is usually described as <b>Mario</b>\'s twin brother. <b>Luigi</b> first appeared in the arcade game Mario Bros., where he was introduced as a main character alongside <b>Mario</b>. Sometimes, <b>Luigi</b> has also been the one who directs the credits, as in Super Mario RPG and Paper Mario. <br/><br/>Since his debut, <b>Luigi</b> has appeared in many games in the Mario series, most of the time accompanying <b>Mario</b> as a central protagonist, but he has also starred as the main character in <b>Mario is Missing!</b> and <b>Luigi\'s Mansion</b>. <br/><br/>In most of the main series games, <b>Luigi</b> usually takes the role of the second player, but he has also occasionally appeared as a main character, either as part of a revealed secret in the game or as an unlockable. While <b>Luigi</b> was originally created as an identical character to <b>Mario</b>, except for being green instead of red, <b>Luigi</b> has developed his own personality and style. <br/><br/><b>Luigi</b> is normally described as cowardly, but once he gathers all his courage, he can be tough and overcome all his fears. He is romantically linked with <b>Princess Daisy</b> in several games.]]></string>
    <string name="PeachDescription"><![CDATA[<b>Princess Peach</b> is the princess of the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b>. She first appeared in Super Mario Bros for NES. <b>Peach</b> was created by <b>Shigeru Miyamoto</b> and is the damsel in distress in most Mario games. Since her debut in Super Mario Bros, <b>Peach</b> has appeared in almost every game in the franchise, becoming one of the most recognizable icons in video games and the most well-known female video game character in the world.<br/><br/>In the Super Mario series, <b>Peach</b> has only been playable in Super Mario Bros 2 and Super Mario 3D World. However, she has been playable in many of the franchise\'s <i>spinoffs</i>, being playable in all Mario Kart, Mario Party, Mario Tennis, Mario Golf, Mario Strikers, and Mario Baseball games, among many others.<br/><br/><b>Peach</b> lives in her castle and handles political affairs in the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b>. Additionally, several <b>Toads</b> such as Master Toadsworth help her manage the kingdom. <b>Peach</b> cares a lot about the citizens of her kingdom, and as seen in <b>Mario &amp; Luigi: Bowser\'s Inside Story</b>, she convenes assemblies to ensure the well-being of the inhabitants of her kingdom from time to time.<br/><br/> She is often kidnapped by <b>Bowser</b> or his minions. However, she always ends up being rescued by <b>Mario</b>. The reasons she is kidnapped by <b>Bowser</b> are because he wants to take control of the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b> and because he is in love with the princess. In fact, <b>Bowser</b> has tried to marry <b>Peach</b> on several occasions. Nonetheless, <b>Bowser</b>\'s feelings are not reciprocated by <b>Peach</b>. However, despite being constantly kidnapped by him, <b>Peach</b> does not show disdain for <b>Bowser</b> and does not hold a grudge, treating him amicably.]]></string>
    <string name="YoshiDescription"><![CDATA[<b>Yoshi</b> is one of the main characters of the franchise. He is a friendly dinosaur belonging to the species of the same name who has helped <b>Mario and Luigi</b>, often being used as a very useful mount that allows them to overcome levels more easily. He has participated in several adventures and has starred in others. He lives on <b>Yoshi\'s Island</b>, a tropical island near the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b>, though he frequently visits the kingdom.<br/><br/> Initially, it was planned for <b>Yoshi</b> to appear in the first Super Mario Bros game as a mount for Mario, but due to the limitations of the NES, he was not implemented. The idea was also intended for Super Mario Bros 3, but again, the limitations of the NES prevented Yoshi from appearing. Finally, <b>Yoshi</b> appeared in the next game of the series, Super Mario World.<br/><br/><b>Yoshi</b> became extremely popular among fans, appearing in numerous games from that time until now, as well as becoming the star of his own video game franchise.]]></string>
    <string name="ToadDescription"><![CDATA[<b>Toad</b> is a character from Nintendo\'s Mario video game series. He is a small humanoid with a mushroom-shaped head. They are peaceful people from the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b>. Like other Mario characters, such as <b>Yoshi</b>, both the species and the main individual are called <b>Toad</b>.<br/><br/>They first appeared in Super Mario Bros, where they said the famous phrase <i>&quot;Thank you Mario / Luigi, but the princess is in another castle&quot;</i> each time <b>Mario</b> reached the end of the first seven castles. In Paper Mario, the <b>Toad Town</b>, the capital of the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b>, appears, where the Toads known as the <b>mushroom people</b> live.<br/><br/>His companion and friendly relationship is with <b>Toadette</b>. <b>Toad</b> is a happy and somewhat childlike character, he is kind and almost never gets angry. He has always found <b>Mario</b> in his rescues of the princess.]]></string>
    <string name="BowserDescription"><![CDATA[<b>Bowser</b> is the main villain of the Super Mario franchise and the most iconic character in video games. He made his debut in the Super Mario Bros video game, and since then he has appeared in the vast majority of the franchise\'s video games.<br/><br/>He is the king and most powerful of the <b>Koopas</b>. He lives in a huge and dangerous castle in the <b>Koopa Kingdom</b>.<b>Bowser</b>\'s goal in most games is to kidnap <b>Princess Peach</b>, whom he is in love with, and to dominate the <b>Mushroom Kingdom</b>, although his plans are always foiled by Mario.<br/><br/><b>Bowser</b> has a son named <b>Bowser Jr</b> (Bowsy in Spain), who wants to follow in his father\'s footsteps and helps him kidnap <b>Peach</b> and fight against <b>Mario</b>. Additionally, <b>Bowser</b> is often accompanied by his seven minions, the <b>Koopalings</b>. To accomplish his goals, <b>Bowser</b> has a large and varied army of loyal minions.]]></string>
</resources>